A Guide to the Office of the Dean of Students Office Administrative Files, 1982-2000
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Office of the Dean of Students Office Administrative Files 1982-2000
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
RG-18/2/1.961
This collection consists of 6,700 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Access restrictions apply only to specific student records under the terms of the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (F.E.R.P.A.).
Acquisition Information
This collection was transferred to the library on 1996 August 5.
Scope and Content Information
Topical files from Dean Robert T. Canevari's office, including the files of Associate Deans and Assistant Deans of Students.
Organization
Series I: General Records, 1982-2000 Boxes 1-15
Series II: V. Shamim Sisson, Associate Dean of Students Boxes 15-16
Series III: Sybil R. Todd, Associate Dean of Students Box 16
Series IV: Annette Gibbs, Associate Dean of Students Boxes 16-19
Series V: Restricted Boxes 20-24
Contents List
- Series I: General Records
  - Algernon Sydney Sullivan Award 1989 (Box 1)
  - Afro-American Affairs, Office of 1990-1991 (Box 1)
  - Office of African-American Affairs--Video on Retention 1990 (Box 1)
  - Asian Student Leaders Conference 1990 (Box 1)
  - Blagden Committee 1991 (Box 1)
  - Gus Blagden Nominees 1991-1992 (Box 1)
  - Gus Blagden Committee 1992 (Box 1)
  - Blagden Nominations 1993 (Box 1)
  - Gus Blagden 1994 (Box 1)
  - Board of Visitors (3 folders) 1990-1993 (Box 1)
  - Budget--Capital Budget Planning 1990-2000 (Box 1)
  - Career Planning and Placement, Office of 1989-1991 (Box 1)
  - Colonnades Handbook, The 1988-1990 (Box 1)
  - Contracted Independent Organization (CIO) 1988-1989 (Box 2)
  - Contracted Independent Organization--Review 1989 (Box 2)
  - Closer Look, A 1992 (Box 2)
  - Common Reading Experience 1989-1992 (Box 2)
  - Comptroller 1987-1990 (Box 2)
  - Convocation (Fall) 1989 (Box 2)
  - Culturefest 1990 (Box 2)
  - Office of the Dean of Students--Budget 1990-1991 (Box 2)
  - Office of the Dean of Students--Budget (Dean of Students, Residence Life, Student Activities) (2 folders) 1991-1993 (Box 2)
  - Office of the Dean of Students--Budget, David Bobbitt, Study of Lesbians, Bisexuals and Gays 1993 (Box 2)
  - Office of the Dean of Students--Budget, First Year Seminar 1991-1992 (Box 2)
  - Office of the Dean of Students--Budget, Newcomb Hall (3 folders) 1990-1993 (Box 2)
  - Office of the Dean of Students--Budget, Programs 1992-1993 (Box 3)
  - Office of the Dean of Students--Budget, Reductions 1990-1992 (Box 3)
  - Office of the Dean of Students--Budget, Residence Life 1990-1991 (Box 3)
  - Office of the Dean of Students--Budget, Variance Reports and Archive Report 1-10830 1991-1992 (Box 3)
  - Office of the Dean of Students--Budget, U-21 Videotaping Project 1992 (Box 3)
  - Office of the Dean of Students--Budget Submission, New Initiatives 1992-1994 (Box 3)
  - Office of the Dean of Students--Expenses, Common Reading Experience 1990-1991 (Box 3)
  - Office of the Dean of Students--Expenses, First Year Seminar 1990-1991 (Box 3)
  - Office of the Dean of Students--Expenses, On Target 1990-1991 (Box 3)
  - Office of the Dean of Students--Expenses, Transfer Student Advisors 1990-1991 (Box 3)
  - Office of the Dean of Students--Annual Report (4 folders) 1977-1980 (Box 3)
  - Office of the Dean of Students--Annual Report (2 folders) (Restricted) 1980-1981 (Box 3)
  - Office of the Dean of Students--Annual Report 1981-1982 (Box 4)
  - Office of the Dean of Students--Annual Report (3 folders) 1989-1991 (Box 4)
  - Office of the Dean of Students--On Call Notebooks 1982-1988 (Box 4)
  - Office of the Dean of Students--Serious Incident Reports (4 folders) (Restricted) 1989-1994 (Box 4)
  - Office of the Dean of Students--On Call List, Emergency 1988-1989-1990 (Box 4)
  - Office of the Dean of Students--Miscellaneous (2 folders) 1991-1992 (Box 4)
  - Office of the Dean of Students--Performance Evaluations for General Faculty in Students Affairs (3 folders) 1989-1991 (Box 4)
  - Office of the Dean of Students--Performance, Planning and Evaluation, Classified 1989-1991 (Box 4)
  - Office of the Dean of Students--Purpose 1988-1989-1991 (Box 4)
  - Office of the Dean of Students--R.T. Canevari: Speeches/Talks (2 folders) 1988-1991 (Box 5)
  - Office of the Dean of Students--Student Life Audio Tape 1991 (Box 5)
  - Office of the Dean of Students--Evaluation (Powers, Spring 1992) 1992 (Box 5)
  - Office of the Dean of Students--Retreat 1992 (Box 5)
  - Entering First Years Proposed Study Project (Mooman) 1992 (Box 5)
  - Exit Interviews (2 folders) (Restricted) 1991-1992 (Box 5)
  - Faculty Senate Executive Council and Comm. On Program Planning 1991 (Box 5)
  - First Year Focus, Multiculturalism Program 1991 (Box 5)
  - First Year Students, Possibility for Establishing a Mandatory Seminar for 1992 (Box 5)
  - Forum on Undergraduate Education 1991-1992 (Box 5)
  - Founders Day Proposal 1991 (Box 5)
  - Fraternities (2 folders) (Restricted) 1990-1993 (Box 5)
  - Fraternity Alumni Council 1991-1993 (Box 5)
  - Virginia Fraternity Alumni Council Membership Roster 1990-1991 (Box 6)
  - Gathering Space 1990 (Box 6)
  - Gooch/Dillard Residential Committee 1989 (Box 6)
  - Graduating Class (4th Year Pres.) (Restricted) 1990-1991 (Box 6)
  - Graduating Class (4th Year Trustees) 1991-1993 (Box 6)
  - Graduating Class Planning 1991 (Box 6)
  - Gray Carrington Candidates 1991 (Box 6)
  - Gray Carrington Committee (3 folders) 1990-1993 (Box 6)
  - Honor Committee (3 folders) 1990-1993 (Box 6)
  - Honor Loan Fund, Ivey F. Lewis (Restricted) 1988-1991 (Box 6)
  - Housing Division (2 folders) 1990-1992 (Box 6)
  - Hunger and Homelessness National Conference 1992 (Box 6)
  - Inter Fraternity Council Clean Up Program 1989 (Box 6)
  - Institute for Substance Abuse Studies (Restricted) 1989-1991 (Box 7)
  - International Student Affairs 1986-1990 (Box 7)
  - Intramural Department 1987-1992 (Box 7)
  - 250th Anniversary of Birth of Thomas Jefferson Committee 1992-1993 (Box 7)
  - Thomas Jefferson's 250th Birthday Account 4-60473 1992 (Box 7)
  - Thomas Jefferson (Rob Coles As) 1992 (Box 7)
  - Judiciary Committee (3 folders) 1990-1993 (Box 7)
  - Judiciary Committee, Jurisdiction Issues 1992 (Box 7)
  - Judiciary Committee, Sexual Assault Investigator/Counsel Training 1992 (Box 7)
  - Judiciary Committee, Working File 1991-1992 (Box 7)
  - The Lawn (2 folders) 1990-1992 (Box 7)
  - The Lawn, West Lawn Scholarship 1989 (Box 7)
  - Lawn Organizing Committee 1991-1992 (Box 7)
  - Lawn Steering Committee 1990-1991 (Box 7)
  - Summer Leadership Program 1991 (Box 7)
  - Leadership 2000 (2 folders) 1992-1993 (Box 8)
  - Littlejohns Incident 1991 (Box 8)
  - Madison House 1988-1991 (Box 8)
  - Madison House Goals 1991-1992 (Box 8)
  - Medical Center Misc. 1986-1988 (Box 8)
  - Students from Mixed Races Meetings 1992-1993 (Box 8)
  - Monroe Hill Residential College 1990-1991 (Box 8)
  - Newcomb Hall Director's Office (2 folders) 1990-1992 (Box 8)
  - Newcomb Hall Facilities Coordinator 1990-1991 (Box 8)
  - UVa. Newspaper Articles Miscellaneous 1990-1992 (Box 8)
  - Newcomb Hall Expansion/Renovation (2 folders) 1991-1992 (Box 9)
  - Parents Weekend 1991 (Box 9)
  - Parents Committee Funding (2 folders) 1990-1992 (Box 9)
  - Parents Committee Funding 1992-1993 (Box 9)
  - Parking, Garage and Bookstore Facility Building Committee 1990 (Box 9)
  - Pavilion VIII Committee 1991-1992 (Box 9)
  - Pep Band Review 1991-1992 (Box 9)
  - Planning--Biennial Evaluation and Planning Report (Office of the Dean of Students and Newcomb) 1988-2000 (Box 9)
  - Planning--Biennial Eval. and Planning Report, Guidance Memorandum 1988 (Box 9)
  - Planning--Biennial Evaluation and Planning Report, Newcomb Hall 1990-1994 (Box 9)
  - Planning--Biennial Evaluation Report and Planning For 1986-1988, 1984-1986 (Box 9)
  - Student Affairs
  - Planning--Biennial Evaluation Report and Planning For 1988-2000, 1986-1988 (Box 9)
  - Vice President for Student Affairs
  - Planning--Biennial Evaluation Report and Planning For 1990-1994, 1988-1990 (Box 9)
  - Office of Vice President for Student Affairs
  - Physical Plant 1990-1991 (Box 9)
  - President's Office (Casteen) (2 folders) 1990-1993 (Box 11)
  - President's Retreat (3 folders) 1990-1992 (Box 11)
  - Provost's Office 1988-1991 (Box 11)
  - Provost Dean's Meetings 1992 (Box 11)
  - Racial Harassment/Homophobic 1990 (Box 11)
  - Racial Awareness Meetings (Provost) 1990-1991 (Box 11)
  - Real People 1991 (Box 11)
  - Recommendations (Other than Students) 1989-1991 (Box 11)
  - Registrar's Office 1990-1991 (Box 11)
  - Religion 1987-1992 (Box 11)
  - Religion--Jewish Student Life Report 1990 (Box 12)
  - Residence Life, Monday Night Series 1988-1990 (Box 12)
  - Virginia Residence Life Staff, Organization and Compensation Survey 1990 (Box 12)
  - Resident Staff (3 folders) 1990-1993 (Box 12)
  - Residential Colleges (New), Committee on 1991 (Box 12)
  - Residential Colleges, Committee on 1991-1992 (Box 12)
  - Residential College Proposal 1990 (Box 12)
  - Residential Life, Committee on (2 folders) 1990-1992 (Box 12)
  - Residential Staff--Serious Incident Reports 1991-1992 (Box 12)
  - Resident Staff- First Year Overage Meetings, Summer 1992 (Box 12)
  - Resident Staff, Summer 1993 (Box 12)
  - Residential Life Plan 1982 (Box 12)
  - Residential Staff Summer Session 1992 (Box 12)
  - Safety and Security (Environmental Health and Safety) 1986-1990 (Box 13)
  - State Council of Higher Education for Virginia (SCHEV) Conference 1992 April (Box 13)
  - State Council of Higher Education for Virginia (SCHEV) Regional Consortia Meetings for Substance Abuse and Sexual Assault 1991-1992 (Box 13)
  - Search Committee, Assistant Dean of Students (Judiciary), Spring 1990 (Box 13)
  - Search Committee, Assistant Dean of Students (Residential Life, 1st Year), Spring 1990 (Box 13)
  - Search Committee, Assistant Dean of Students (Student Organizations), Spring 1990 (Box 13)
  - Sexual Assault (Miscellaneous) 1990-1991 (Box 13)
  - Sororities 1990-1991 (Box 13)
  - Student Activities Business Manager 1986-1990 (Box 13)
  - Vice President for Student Affairs--Ernest H. Ern 1990-1991 (Box 13)
  - Vice President for Student Affairs--Ernest H. Ern 1991-1992-1993 (Box 13)
  - Vice President for Student Affairs, Assistant--Peter Stark 1991-1993 (Box 13)
  - Student Council (3 folders) 1990-1993 (Box 14)
  - Student Organizations (2 folders) 1990-1993 (Box 14)
  - Operation Smile Conference 1993 (Box 14)
  - National Campaign Against Hunger and Homelessness 1990 (Box 14)
  - Student Council--Ethnic/Racial Environment 1989 (Box 14)
  - Substance Abuse Studies Council 1992-1993 (Box 14)
  - Substance Abuse and Sexual Assault, Campus Team on 1992-1993 (Box 14)
  - Substance Abuse and Sexual Assault on College Campuses, Governor's Task Force 1991-1992 (Box 14)
  - Summer Session/Dean of Students 1990 (Box 15)
  - University Union (3 folders) 1990-1993 (Box 15)
  - University Union Arts Board Bread and Puppet Theater 1991 (Box 15)
  - View Conference 1991 (Box 15)
  - Viewpoint 1991-1992 (Box 15)
  - Virginia Tech Visit 1992 (Box 15)
  - Vouching 1987-1988 (Box 15)
  - Wellness Committee 1991-1993 (Box 15)
  - Women, 20th Anniversary 1990-1991 (Box 15)
  - X- Rated Films 1977-1987 (Box 15)
  - Yellow Cab Program (5 folders) (Restricted) 1988-1993 (Box 15)
- Series II: V. Shamim Sisson, Associate Dean of Students
  - Contracted Independent Organization 1991 (Box 15)
  - Contracted Independent Organization --Correspondence 1987-1990 (Box 15)
  - Contracted Independent Organization --Final Report 1990-1991 (Box 15)
  - Contracted Independent Organization --Implementation 1990-1991 (Box 16)
  - Contracted Independent Organization --News Clips 1987 (Box 16)
- Series III: Sybil R. Todd, Associate Dean of Students
  - Exit Interviews (11 folders) (Restricted) 1986-1990 (Box 16)
- Series IV: Annette Gibbs, Associate Dean of Students
  - Annual Reports--Annette Gibbs (3 folders) 1981-1984 (Box 16)
  - Easter's Weekend 1976-1982 (Box 16)
  - First-Year Orientation--Evaluation Reports 1974-1978 (Box 16)
  - Media Board of Directors 1976-1980 (Box 16)
  - Observing Dining Hall Addition Building Committee 1982-1984 (Box 16)
  - On Grounds: A Guide For Planning Activities--6 volumes 1976-1983 (Box 16)
  - Orientation 1983 (Box 16)
  - Student Activities Survey 1986 (Box 17)
  - Student Recreation Building Committee 1975-1976 (Box 17)
  - University Union--Annual Report (2 folders) 1982-1984 (Box 17)
  - University Union--Budget 1984-1985 (Box 17)
  - University Union--Biennial Evaluation and Planning Report 1984 (Box 17)
  - University Union--Concessions / Amplified Music (2 folders) 1983-1985 (Box 17)
  - University Union--Concessions 1984-1985 (Box 17)
  - University Union--Correspondence (2 folders) 1981-1983 (Box 17)
  - University Union--Correspondence 1984-1985 (Box 17)
  - University Union--Governing Board (4 folders) 1982-1986 (Box 17)
  - University Union--President's Committee--Minutes of Meetings 1980-1983 (Box 17)
  - University Union--President's Committee--Minutes of Meetings (2 folders) 1983-1985 (Box 18)
  - University Union--Student Fee Project 1981-1982 (Box 18)
  - University Union--Summer Session 1978-1983 (Box 18)
  - University Union Committees--Cinematheque 1982-1983 (Box 18)
  - University Union Committees--Computer Use 1982-1983 (Box 18)
  - University Union Committees--Crosswinds 1981-1983 (Box 18)
  - University Union Committees--Fine Arts 1979-1983 (Box 18)
  - University Union Committees--Graduate (Restricted) 1979-1983 (Box 18)
  - University Union Committees--Minority Cultures 1982-1983 (Box 18)
  - University Union Committees--Newcomb Hall 1982-1983 (Box 18)
  - University Union Committees--Off Grounds Committee 1983-1985 (Box 18)
  - University Union Committees--Pavilion XI 1979-1983 (Box 18)
  - University Union Committees--PK German 1980-1983 (Box 18)
  - University Union Committees--Publicity Network 1982-1983 (Box 18)
  - University Union Committees--Resources 1982-1983 (Box 18)
  - University Union Committees--Self-Study 1976-1982 (Box 18)
  - University Union Committees--Short Course 1982-1983 (Box 18)
  - University Union Committees--Speakers (2 folders) 1982-1990 (Box 19)
  - University Union Committees--Student Activities 1981-1983 (Box 19)
  - University Union Committees--Travel 1982-1983 (Box 19)
  - University Union Committees--Ushers (Restricted) 1982-1983 (Box 19)
  - Women's Student Association Correspondence 1942-1975 (Box 19)
- Series V: Restricted (Box Boxes 20-24)